# Austin J. Hunt

Versatile engineer with 5+ years of hands-on experience in full stack web dev, distributed systems, networking, cloud architecture, server administration, and container orchestration, with a specially tuned eye for automation and a killer work ethic, seeking work outside of higher ed with a vibrant and inspired team on high-impact software. I want to help people.

**EXPERIENCE** 

**DEC 2019 - PRESENT:** Digital Communications Developer / Webmaster - College of Charleston, Charleston, SC/Remote

- Lead weekly IT meetings for 2+ years & train new employees.
- Daily web support through ITSM ticketing and Zoom/Teams meetings.
- Create training videos & KB resources (e.g., for new SharePoint Intranet, using Google Analytics, using Dubbot, etc.)
- Correspond with 10+ external software vendors and leverage SDKs/APIs for smooth enterprise system integrations.
- Reduce software costs by \$60K+ with automation scripting, full-stack web dev (5+ apps), API dev, & SharePoint administration
- Build, maintain, & document 30+ APIs, applications, & scripts to support internal processes and 50+ business units with automation (using tools like Selenium, APIs, webhooks, cron).
- Script 5+ cross-environment data syncs (cloud to cloud, cloud to on prem, on prem to cloud).
- Develop & document WP theme for today.charleston.edu with custom plugins to support search across legacy and redesigned sites.
- Build high-value front-facing web features for charleston.edu (e.g., "meet your counselor" with SchoolDigger integration, and "library crowd meter" for COVID response) to serve public and internal audiences
- Save 20+ man-hours a year by building CI/CD pipelines across
  5+ key projects, including distributed web server configs for charleston.edu. Cut deployment times by 90% with GH Actions.
- Evangelize use of Docker, Ansible, Git, GH Actions, CI/CD, PR reviews, & GH Copilot within IT. Advocate MS Flow & Power Apps for streamlining campus business processes in O365.
- Centralize IT API documentation and testing in Postman for more efficient internal collaboration.
- Use PowerShell to **automate** repetitive site provisioning and templating for new (2023) **SharePoint intranet**.
- Securely maintain 30+ on-prem & cloud servers (Windows Server, RHEL, Ubuntu). Install & renew SSL certs (on-prem & SaaS). Backup/restore SQL databases. Monitor logs, respond to DoS attacks, & help plan more redundant web infrastructure.
- Implement analytics dashboarding in Splunk. Administer Google Analytics (3 & 4); set up and use Google Tag Manager and Google Programmable Search Engine on charleston.edu sites.
- Administer Osano for cookie consent management, & Pantheon for WP hosting of 25+ large sites.
- Configure RBAC and SSO with Azure AD for custom and COTS apps to adhere to the least privilege access model.

MAY 2019 - DEC 2019: Temp - College of Charleston, Charleston, SC

- Implement network monitoring and alerting for 1000+ hosts with Icinga.
- Configure distributed infrastructure with Ansible.
- Create custom service checks with NCPA, ICMP, SNMP, and SSH
- Script webhook-driven MS Teams alerts with Python.
- Collaborate with a networking team for troubleshooting and

25 Draper Street Apt 103 Greenville, SC 29611

864.353.3171

austincodescleanly@gmail.com

austinjhunt.com linkedin.com/in/huntaj github.com/austinjhunt austinjhunt.medium.com

### **SKILLS**

Learning & working quickly

Prioritizes clean code, clear documentation, and maintainable solutions

Clear communicator, both in writing and in person

Broad range of frontend and backend languages, including JS, Python, Bash, PowerShell, Go, PHP, HTML/CSS/Sass, TS, Java

Web frameworks and libraries like Django, Express.js, React, Flask, Next.js

Secure cloud architecture, Linux administration

Implementing RBAC, SSO, OAuth2/OIDC flows, MFA

Network troubleshooting, monitoring and alerting config

Container management, orchestration with Kubernetes/K8s

Cloud platforms - Google Cloud Platform, Azure, AWS (IAM, S3, Lambda, EBS, EC2, ACM, Cloudwatch, & more)

Functional **and** Object-Oriented Programming

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

2024: Certified Kubernetes Administrator 2024: (In Progress) AWS Certified Solutions Architect

**2021**: Docker Certified Associate **2021**: Certified Associate Python Programmer

#### **EDUCATION**

**MAY 2021 - DEC 2022**: Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN — *M.S. Computer Science*, *4.0* 

**AUG 2015 - MAY 2019:** College of Charleston, Charleston, SC— B.S. Computer Science, 3.95

## **PROJECTS**

scaling.

- Build and maintain a Django SSO-enabled app for the team to manage their own server monitoring.

- Integrate Icinga with Netbox for network hardware monitoring.

**OCT 2017 - MAY 2019**: Student Network Engineer - College of Charleston, Charleston, SC

- Handle zero-downtime install and config of Juniper switches and power supplies.

 Configure new UPS NICs & automate mass firmware upgrades with Python.

- Manage inventory & train new employees

OCT 2023 - PRESENT: NovaBrains.ai -LLM-assisted, LMS-integrated digital textbook platform for educators and learners alike for building and using engaging, interactive courses. In collaboration with Ayman Hajja, PhD.

Stack: AWS (CLI, SAM, R53, EBS, S3, Lambda, Cloud- watch, IAM), Python, JS, GitHub Actions, React, Material UI, Django REST Framework, OpenAI ChatGPT API, Swagger, Slack, Jira, GCP, reCAPTCHA, Postman, OAuth2, ToTP

**Roles**: Cloud architect, devops engineer, full-stack developer, cofounder.

JUNE 2024 - PRESENT: StudyRocket.ai - AI-powered, on-the-fly interactive quiz generation about anything you want to study. In collaboration with Ayman Hajja, PhD.

Stack: AWS (CLI, SAM, R53, EBS, S3, Lambda, Cloudwatch, IAM), Python, JS, GitHub Actions, React, Material UI, Django REST Framework, OpenAI ChatGPT API, Swagger, Slack, Jira, GCP, reCAPTCHA, Postman

Roles: Cloud architect, devops engineer, full-stack co-developer, cofounder June 2024 - Present

JULY 2019 - PRESENT: sketchyactivity.com - Art portfolio and commission portal SPA hosted for free on GitHub.

Stack: GitHub Pages, React, GA4

Roles: Solo web developer.

JUNE 2023 - PRESENT: jerrywestonmize.com - WordPress-based music lessons payment qateway

**Stack:** Linode, WordPress (PHP, JS, CSS), WP Amelia for Payments, Colibri, custom plugins, GA4

**Roles**: Freelance full stack web developer, web support